Arthur Lakes Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
Arthur Lakes Archives
1877-1879
VPAR.000269
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
100
A Collection of Arthur Lakes artwork from his time serving as a collecter for O.C.Marsh.
Lakes, Arthur, 1844-1917
Biographical Sketch
Arthur Lakes (21 December 1844 ? 21 November 1917) was a notable geologist, artist, writer, teacher and minister. He captured much of his geological and palaeontological field work in sketches and watercolours. He was a part-time professor at what later became the Colorado School of Mines when he sent a fossilized vertebra specimen (from the Morrison Formation of Dakota, U.S.) to Othniel Charles Marsh at the Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History in 1877. He was then employed by Marsh as a field worker to seek other fossils. These fossils and sites are recorded in his artwork. He worked for O.C Marsh from 1877-1880. During this time, he also worked as a teacher at what is now the Colorado School of Mines and as a clergyman. When he retired from fossil hunting, he went on to work for the U.S. Geological Survey.
Description of the Material
The Arthur Lakes Archives most notably include water colors and sketches of localities and specimens from his collecting trips. As well as a small amount of correspondence and field notes.
Drawings; Correspondence; Field notebooks; Yale Peabody Museum; Yale University
- Correspondence, 1877-1879; Series I
  - O.C. Marsh Correspondence., 1877-1879; 000273
    - Postcard from Arthur Lakes to O. C. Marsh dated 22 March 1878. Postcard from Arthur Lakes to O. C. Marsh dated 22 March 1878, 002788
- Drawings, 1877-1879; Series II
  - Locality Drawings, etc., 1877-1879; 000275
  - Specimen Drawings, etc., 1877-1879; 000276
- Field Notes, 1877-1879; Series III
  - Field Notes., 002755
- Miscellaneous, 1877-1879; Series IV
  - Miscellaneous., 002756